<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>

<sect1 id="ch07-consolidated">
  <title>Consolidated.html</title>
  <?dbhtml filename="consolidated.html"?>

  <para>
    The consolidated page provides a list of our advisories since we began
    to create them. They are numbered within releases, in each case newest
    first. This page lives in <filename
    class="directory">blfs/advisories</filename> but it is common to both
    LFS and BLFS.
  </para>

  <para>
    Create the details for the next available advisory number. The top part
    of the page contains a lot of commented items which can be used as a
    template, but if there are previous advisories for this package it may be
    easier to copy details from one of those.
  </para>

  <para>
    As well as the number, and the sa-NN.N-nnn link, each entry has a date and
    a severity. Where upstream has assigned a severity we normally go with that.
    If a source such as NVD has assigned a severity, consider if it is
    appropriate (our default is 'High' even for Denial of Service on non-server
    programs).
  </para>

  <para>
    Where one or more CVEs have been issued, it may be useful to link to NVD if
    that provides details, or else to any other reliable source which explains
    the vulnerability (i.e. google for it). If the details are not public, you
    might not be able to find a suitable external link. But for packages which
    provide their own advisories it is good to link to those.
  </para>

  <para>
    Render the page, check that the links (external to applications, and internal
    to the sysv and systemd books) work correctly and that what you have written
    and pasted makes sense.
  </para>

  <para>
    It might be beneficial to commit the change to consolidated.html at this
    point, so that you own the advisory number (e.g. if you think other people
    may also be updating advisories). In that case it is probably best to do only
    one if you have several, and to then update the page for the current release.
  </para>

</sect1>
