<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>

<sect1 id="ch07-introduction">
  <title>Introduction</title>
  <?dbhtml filename="introduction.html"?>

  <para>
    In both LFS and BLFS we try to advise our users of security
    vulnerabilities. Sometimes vulnerabilities are mentioned in a release
    announcement, at other times they are noticed later.
  </para>

  <para>
    The current advisories point to the development books, with past advisories
     pointing to the numbered books (rather than to'stable' ). You will probably
    need to create some symlinks in wherever you render the books so that both
    versions of the current LFS and BLFS books point to your local copies so that
    you can check them before pushing. If you have local renders of the current
    released books you can also link to those. Because
    <filename>consolidated.html</filename> is located in the BLFS book, you will
    need to make a special symlink to get to that from your local LFS advisories.
  </para>

  <para>
    For historical reasons, the links at rivendell point to 'svn' and 'systemd'
    for the current books.
  </para>

  <para>
    Normally we will raise a security advisory once we have a tested fix in the
    appropriate book (LFS or BLFS), i.e. a newer version, or a patch. However
    sometimes a vulnerability remains open for a long time and we may choose to
    suggest a workaround such as "do not use this feature of the package".
  </para>

  <para>
    We try to provide enough details to enable users to decide if they need to
    update as soon as possible, including a vulnerability assessment and any
    details we can find. If upstream provides an assessment of the severity we
    will normally use that. Otherwise we must search around for details. If
    details of a CVE are publically visible there might be a rating at
    <ulink url="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/search"/> although sometimes that site
    regards issues as Moderate when a rating of High might be appropriate. If in
    doubt, our default rating is High.
  </para>

  <para>
    In theory, a user of a recent past version of the book can look at our
    current and previous vulnerabilities and see every fixed vulnerability which
    affects a package. In practice it is not always clear that a newer version
    has fixed a vulnerability - if that comes to light after we have made a
    release with a newer version of the package such items might be ignored on
    the grounds that most users have already looked at the previous
    vulnerabilities and are unlikely to notice new additions - for example
    a vulenrability in flac-3.2 was fixed in flac-3.3 but not publically
    mentioned. In such cases we can add a 'Late Advisories' section between the
    advisories for the current book and the previous advisories - see 10.0-102
    in <filename>consolidated.html</filename> and the corresponding entry in
    <filename>10.0.html</filename>. In these cases, the best way to alert users
    is to announce the advisory on the lfs-support and blfs-support lists.
  </para>

  <para>
    From time to time we may become aware that the details of an advisory should
    be changed, e.g. it might be that it is invalid for some reason (e.g. never
    in a released version, or only applicable to windows). When this happens we
    can modify the existing item and change the 'Date' entry to 'Updated' with
    the current date.
  </para>

  <para>For day to day updates to advisories the files are organized into:</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <filename>blfs/advisories/consolidated.html</filename> (shared between
        LFS and BLFS).
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <filename>lfs/advisories/NN.N.html</filename> (for any LFS advisories
        since the current (NN.N) release).
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <filename>bfs/advisories/NN.N.html</filename> (for any BLFS advisories
        since the current (NN.N) release).
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>There are two parts to creating an advisory:</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Taking the next available number to create an entry in
        <filename>consolidated.html</filename> containing the necessary details.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Adding summary advisory details for this version of LFS or BLFS.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>
    <emphasis>Much of any new item will be copied from a template or from an
    earlier advisory. It is important to take your time when reviewing what
    you have created, to see that it reads and links correctly.</emphasis>
  </para>

</sect1>
